UKANDIE SUNDAY

Front End Developer

● Uyo, Nigeria 🔰 +2349053588942 💌 ukandieudo202@gmail.com 📊 Visit my LinkedIn

♥ Visit my GitHub

Visit my portfolio

Summary

I am Ukandie Sunday, a creative Front End Developer with over two years of experience, consistently learning, building and contributing to teams, driving great results. I'm proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Redux, and other modern frontend technologies.

Education

Federal University of Ndufu Alike(AE-FUNAI), Ebonyi State, Nigeria. .

2017 - 2021

Bachelor's Degree in Accounting.

Abakaliki, Ebonyi State

Work Experience

Moregift Jan 2024 - June 2024

Front End Developer, Intern — Remote (Canada)

- Developed responsive and user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, etc.
- Translated designs on figma to clean, maintainable and functional code.
- Documented development processes and project progress.
- Assisted in building complex features and troubleshooting issues within the code base with constructive feed backs.
- Collaborated seamlessly with design and backend teams to integrate frontend features.
- Built numerous email templates and marketing campaign contents.

Solacatech (Freelancing Company)

June 2024 - Present

Junior Front End Developer, Contract — Remote (Nigeria)

- Delivered high-performance, SEO-optimized websites tailored to client requirements. Converted email templates and SEO marketing contents.
- Tested and debugged websites for efficiency and cross-browser compatibility.
- Integrated backend technologies such as Node.js and PHP.
- Translated Figma wire frames into production-ready code with responsive user interfaces.
- Maintained version control using Git and GitHub.
- Participated in code reviews, weekends stand-ups, and agile development processes.
- Set up project environments and configured tools like Webpack, Babel, and ESLint.
- Kept up-to-date with frontend technology trends.

Projects

Company Marketing website | React.js, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Context API, Material UI, etc Link

- This multiple pages website showcases the services offer by SOLACATECH Company, e.g Web development, Mobile development, UX/UI design, IT consulting, Database Management, among others.
- Built with mobile first approach design, very responsive, SEO-optimized and cross-browser compatible.

E-Commerce Website | React.js, CSS, Redux Link

May 2023

- This e-commerce website allows users to purchase cars, including seamless features such as add to cart functionality.
- Navigate different views, user authentication, and privacy measures, etc.

Quick-Seller Admin Dashboard (In Progress) | React.js, TypeScript, Tailwind css, Shaden UI, etc Link

Aug. 2024

- This admin dashboard manages these activities in the website, such as Vendors sales partnership, affiliates, dispatch riders.
- Users management and tracking of daily activity flows, etc.

Moregift's Financial Portal Website | Next.js, TypeScript, Sass, Material UI Link

Feb. 2024

• This website showcases the financial services offer by moregift, with a link to the mobile app Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript,.

Frameworks/Libaries: React.js, Next.js, Sass, Tailwind Css, Redux, Context API, Shadon Ui, Material UI, Testing

Tools: Vs Code, Figma, cypress, ClickUp, Swagger UI, Git, GitHub, PostMan, Canva, photoshop

Experience Working With: Nodejs, PHP, REST API, Python, JSON.

Soft Skills: Analytical skills, Problem-solving, Time management, Excellent verbal and written communication, Team work, Creativity.